A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Child Development and Preventive Care, SG 3, Series 6 FA1463
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Child Development and Preventive Care, SG 3, Series 6
1993-2003
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA1463
13.11 Cubic Feet 34 letter-size document boxes, 1 half-letter document box.
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Commonwealth Fund records were donated to RAC in 1985. The initial transfer of archival records to RAC began in 1986, and transfers continue on a regular basis. This series was transferred to RAC as accession 2007:055.
Scope and Contents
This series documents the work of the Commonwealth Fund Child Development and Preventive Care department, including the Youth Mentoring Program. The majority of the material is grant administration files. These records often include documentation of: proposals, administration and budget, grant products, related correspondence and background material. A limited selection of meeting records and program files is also included.
- National Public Health-Hospital Institute (92-31) - Grant Products (Box 1, Folder 1)
- George Washington University - Rosenbaum (980772) - Proposal Development, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- George Washington University - Rosenbaum (980772), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Pediatric Parenting Project - Regalado (990229), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- FACCT - Bethell (980498) - Child and Adolescent Health Measurement Initiative Promoting Healthy Development Measurement Set - Administration and Budget, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- FACCT - Bethell (980498) - Child and Adolescent Health Measurement Initiative Promoting Healthy Development Measurement Set - Proposal Development, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- FACCT - Bethell (980498) - Child and Adolescent Health Measurement Initiative Promoting Healthy Development Measurement Set - Articles and Background (Box 2, Folder 4)
- FACCT - Bethell (980498) - Child and Adolescent Health Measurement Initiative Promoting Healthy Development Measurement Set, 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- FACCT - Bethell (980498) - Promoting Healthy Development Quality Measures Advisory Team, 1998 August 14 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- FACCT - Bethell (980498) - Advisory Group 1, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- FACCT - Bethell (980498) - Advisory Group 2, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- FACCT - Bethell (980498) - Advisory Group 3, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- FACCT - Bethell (980498) - Child and Adolescent Health Measurement Initiative Promoting Healthy Development Measurement Set - Grant Products, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
- Alliance for Health Reform - Guthree (20000717) - Medicaid Working for Children (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Alliance for Health Reform - Medicaid And Child Development: Understanding Medicaid's Role for Young Children - Tape 1, 2002 July 12; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 94 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 9967)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access copy available.
- Alliance for Health Reform - Medicaid And Child Development: Understanding Medicaid's Role for Young Children - Tape 2, 2002 July 12; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 11 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 9968)
- North Carolina Department of Health and Human Services - Yeager (20000382) - Building State Medicaid Capacity for Child Development Services, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- North Carolina Department of Health and Human Services - Yeager (20000382) - Building State Medicaid Capacity for Child Development Services - Grant Products, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- North Carolina Department of Health and Human Services - Yeager (20000382) - Building State Medicaid Capacity for Child Development Services - Grant Products - Site Visit (Box 4, Folder 4)
- North Carolina Department of Health and Human Services - Yeager (20010466) - Building State Medicaid Capacity for Child Development Services, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- North Carolina Department of Health and Human Services - Yeager (20010466) - Building State Medicaid Capacity for Child Development Services - Grant Products, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
- North Carolina Department of Health and Human Services - Yeager (20010466) - Building State Medicaid Capacity for Child Development Services - Grant Products, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Healthy Steps Interactive Multimedia Training and Resource Kit, Independent Production Fund - Zbar (990470), 2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Healthy Steps for Young Children Program, Sustainability and Expansion Accomplishments, Advocate Health Care - Lee (20000579), 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Healthy Steps Multimedia Kit Conference Attendance Grant - Levine (20000760), 2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- AMCHP - Varela (20020329 PDF) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Johns Hopkins University - Healthy Steps Evaluation 1997-1998 (980143) - Administration (Box 6, Folder 6)
- KTY Meetings 1998 - January 30, 1998 Johns Hopkins Data Research - Baltimore (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Johns Hopkins University - Healthy Steps Evaluation 1997-1998 (980143) - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Johns Hopkins University - Healthy Steps Evaluation 1997-1998 (980143) - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Johns Hopkins University - Healthy Steps Evaluation 1997-1998 (980143) - Grant Products (Box 7, Folder 2-5)
- Johns Hopkins University - Evaluation Instruments (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Johns Hopkins University - Healthy Steps Evaluation 1997-1998 (980143) - Working Papers Series (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Johns Hopkins University - Healthy Steps Evaluation 1997-1998 (980143) - Working Papers Series (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Johns Hopkins University - Healthy Steps Evaluation 1997-1998 (980143) - Enrollment Tables (Box 8, Folder 2-4)
- Johns Hopkins University - Healthy Steps Evaluation Phase 3 - 1997-1998 Grant (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Healthy Steps Enrollment Tables (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
- Johns Hopkins University - Healthy Steps Evaluation 1997-1998 (980143) - Grant Products (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Pittsburgh Site Self Reporting Meeting - Children's Hospital Pittsburgh, Healthy Steps Site Visit, 1996 August 30 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Shanna Shulman Contract, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Presentations - Site Summary (Box 10, Folder 3)
- ICF - Monitoring Visits 1997-1998 (970269): Questions, Templates, Protocols (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Site Visits 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Healthy Steps Program, Ford Bend Family Health Center, Hogg Foundation, Richmond, TX, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Healthy Steps Monitoring Site Visit - University of Texas, Austin, TX (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Healthy Steps Monitoring Site Visit - San Antonio Metropolitan Health District, San Antonio, TX, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Healthy Steps Monitoring Site Visit - McLeod Medical Center, South Carolina (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Healthy Steps Monitoring Site Visit - Florence, South Carolina (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Healthy Steps Monitoring Site Visit - Amarillo, TX (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
- Healthy Steps Monitoring Site Visit - Greater Houston Foundation, TX (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Healthy Steps Monitoring Site Visit - Hogg Foundation, Texas Children's Hospital (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Healthy Steps Monitoring Site Visit Reports, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
- Healthy Steps - Site Visit Reports, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Hospital Youth Menotoring Program Final Report, 1997-1999 (970939) (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Dorothy Rader Pool Health Care Trust: Allentown, PA (Box 12, Folder 3)
- ICF Monitoring Site Visit Reports (Box 12, Folder 4-6)
- ICF - Monitoring Visits (970269), 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Monitoring Site Visit Reports, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Monitoring Site Visit Report, 1997-1998 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Independent Production Fund (IPF) - Zbar (990470) - Multimedia Training Package for a Child Development Approach in Pediatric Practices, Phase III - Proposal and Public Relations, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Independent Production Fund (IPF) - Zbar (990470) - Multimedia Training Package for a Child Development Approach in Pediatric Practices, Phase III - Correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Independent Production Fund (IPF) - Zbar (990470) - Multimedia Training Package for a Child Development Approach in Pediatric Practices, Phase III - Administration and Budget, 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Independent Production Fund (IPF) - Zbar (990470) - Multimedia Training Package for a Child Development Approach in Pediatric Practices, Phase III - Grant Products, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
- Independent Production Fund (IPF) - Zbar (990470) - Multimedia Training Package for a Child Development Approach in Pediatric Practices, Phase III - Grant Products, 1999-2000 (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
- Boston University - Zuckerman (20010114) - Healthy Steps Training for Pediatric Clinicians, Year 5, 2000-2001 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Boston University - Zuckerman (20010114) - Healthy Steps Training for Pediatric Clinicians, Year 5 - Grant Products (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Boston University - Zuckerman (20010114) - Healthy Steps Training for Pediatric Clinicians, Year 5 - Grant Products (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Beal (20010746) - Measures of Health Care Quality for Children (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Zero to Three - Fenichel (20000104) - Assessing Infant-Toddler Development in Context, Zero to Three (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Tonniges (20010006) - The Pediatricians Role in Tackling Inequalities in Child Health: A Joint Meeting of the AAP and the Royal College of Paediatrics and Child Health, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Brazelton Institute - Nugent (20000135) - Developing a Clinical Version of the Neonatal Behavioral Assessment Scale, 1999-2002 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- State of Washington, Department of Social and Health Services (20020590) - State of Washington ABCD Projects (Box 15, Folder 6)
- State of Washington, Department of Social and Health Services (20010465) (Box 15, Folder 7)
- State of Washington, Department of Social and Health Services (20000380) (Box 15, Folder 8)
- State of Washington, Department of Social and Health Services - Multiple Grants, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- State of Washington, Department of Social and Health Services - Multiple Grants, 2001-2002 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- State of Washington, Department of Social and Health Services (20020590) - State of Washington ABCD Projects (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
- State of Washington, Department of Social and Health Services (20000380), 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- State of Washington, Department of Social and Health Services (20000380), 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Foundation for Accountability (FACCT, Inc.) (20010583) - Practice-Level Promoting Healthy Development Survey (PHDS), 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 2-5)
- Foundation for Accountability (FACCT, Inc.) (20010583) - Practice-Level Promoting Healthy Development Survey (PHDS), 2002-2003 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
- State of Vermont, Agency of Human Services - Wallace-Brodeur - Building State Medicaid Capacity to Provide Child Development Services, Year 1 (20000384), 1999-2003 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- State of Vermont, Agency of Human Services - Wallace-Brodeur - Building State Medicaid Capacity to Provide Child Development Services, Year 1 (20000384) - Grant Products, 2000-2001 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- State of Vermont, Agency of Human Services - Wallace-Brodeur - Building State Medicaid Capacity to Provide Child Development Services, Year 2 (20010463), 2001-2002 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- State of Vermont, Agency of Human Services - Wallace-Brodeur - Building State Medicaid Capacity to Provide Child Development Services, Year 2 (20010463) - Grant Products, 2001-2002 (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
- State of Vermont, Agency of Human Services - Wallace-Brodeur - Building State Medicaid Capacity to Provide Child Development Services, Year 3 (20020592) (Box 19, Folder 5)
- State of Vermont, Agency of Human Services - Wallace-Brodeur - Building State Medicaid Capacity to Provide Child Development Services, Year 3 (20020592) (Box 20, Folder 1)
- State of Vermont, Agency of Human Services - Wallace-Brodeur - Building State Medicaid Capacity to Provide Child Development Services, Year 3 (20020592) - Grant Products, 2002-2003 (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
- Utah Department of Health - Deily - Assuming Better Child Health and Development, Year 1 (20000381), 2000-2001 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Utah Department of Health - Deily - Assuming Better Child Health and Development, Year 1 (20000381) - Grant Products, 2000-2001 (Box 20, Folder 5-6)
- Utah Department of Health - Deily - Assuming Better Child Health and Development, Year 2 (20010464), 2001-2002 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Utah Department of Health - Deily - Assuming Better Child Health and Development, Year 2 (20010464) - Grant Products, 2001-2002 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Utah Department of Health - Deily - Assuming Better Child Health and Development, Year 3 (20020591), 2002-2003 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Utah Department of Health - Deily - Assuming Better Child Health and Development, Year 3 (20020591) - Grant Products, 2002-2003 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Youth Program, 1990s (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Albert Einstein Medical Center (96027, 94-31), 1997-1998 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Allegheny University of the Health Sciences (96922), 1996-1998 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Hahnemann University Hospital (96033, 94-37), 1994-1998 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Barnes Hospital (96988, 96028, 94-32) (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Beth Israel Medical Center (96989, 96029, 94-33) (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Cedar-Sinai Medical Center (96990, 96030, 94-34), 1994-1997 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Duke University Medical Center (96991, 96031, 94-35), 1993-1998 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Elmhurst Hospital (96032, 94-36) (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Greater Southeast Healthcare System (97064) (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Greater Southeast Healthcare System (96622) - Proposal (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Greater Southeast Healthcare System (96622), 1996-2000 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Institute for Educational Leadership (970644), 1997-1998 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Institute for Educational Leadership (970644) - Grant Products, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Iowa Methodist Medical Center (96994, 96026, 94-123), 1994-1998 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Johns Hopkins Hospital (970939), 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Johns Hopkins Hospital (970939) - Grant Products, 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Johns Hopkins Hospital Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) (970647), 1997-1999 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Evaluation of Greater Southeast Healthcare System School-To-Work Transition Program (STW) - Phase III (96172) (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Evaluation of Greater Southeast Healthcare System School-To-Work Transition Program (STW) - Phase III (96172) - Kathryn Taaffe Young File, 1996-1999 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Evaluation of Greater Southeast Healthcare System School-To-Work Transition Program (STW) - Phase III (96172) - Grant Products, 1996-1999 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Lewin-VHI, Inc. - Evaluation of Greater Southeast Healthcare System School-To-Work Transition Program (STW), 1995 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Maine Medical Center (96994, 96034, 94-38), 1994-1998 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- MDRC Career Academy Programs, Phase 2 (96813), 1996-1999 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- MDRC Career Academy Programs, Phase 2 (96813) - Grant Products, 1996-1999 (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
- MDRC Career Academy Programs, Phase 2 (96813) - Grant Products, 1996-1999 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- The Metropolitan Health System (96035, 94-39), 1994-1997 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- University of Michigan Hospitals (96036, 96995, 94-40), 1994-1999 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Mississippi Institutions of Higher Learning (90-38), 1989-1996 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Mississippi Institutions of Higher Learning (90-38) - Correspondence and Grant Products, 1993-1996 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Mt. Sinai Medical Center (96037, 96996, 94-41), 1993-1997 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- National Coalition of Community Foundations for Youth (CCFY) (95412), 1995-1998 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- National Coalition of Community Foundations for Youth (CCFY) (95412) (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
- The Commonwealth Fund-Johns Hopkins Hospital - Mentoring News, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Youth Mentoring Program Publications (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Assessment of Healthy Steps Learning Materials, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Assessment of Healthy Steps Learning Materials, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Independent Production Fund (IPF) (980486) - A Multimedia Training Package for a Developmental Approach in Pediatric Practices, Phase II, 1998-1999 (Box 28, Folder 2-4)
- Independent Production Fund (IPF) (990470) - A Multimedia Training Package Developmental Practices, Phase III, 1998-1999 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Coalition of Community Foundations for Youth (CCFY) (95412), 1995 (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Brandeis University - Center for Corporate and Education Initiatives (10170), 1990s (Box 29, Folder 3)
- University of Pennsylvania (94-82), 1994-1998 (Box 29, Folder 4)
- University of Pennsylvania (94-82) - Articles (Box 29, Folder 5)
- University of Pennsylvania (94-82) - Background Materials, 1993-1994 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
- University of Pennsylvania (94-82) - Grant Products, 1995-1999 (Box 30, Folder 3-4)
- Princeton Survey Research Associates - Successful Mentoring Relationships (97045), 1997-1998 (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Princeton Survey Research Associates - Successful Mentoring Relationships (97045) - Grant Products, 1997-1998 (Box 31, Folder 2-4)
- Princeton Survey Research Associates - Successful Mentoring Relationships (97045) -Banners, 1998 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- University of Pennsylvania (94-82) - Background Materials, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Public Private Ventures - Lewin (96171) - Lessons Learned from the Hospital Youth Mentoring Program, 1996-1998 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Public Private Ventures - Lewin (96171) - Lessons Learned from the Hospital Youth Mentoring Program - Grant Products, 1996-1998 (Box 32, Folder 4-5)
- Public Private Ventures - Lewin (96171) - Lessons Learned from the Hospital Youth Mentoring Program - Grant Products, 1998 (Box 33, Folder 1)
- Public Private Ventures (96621) - Mentoring Youth: The Community Change for Youth Development Project, Phase II, 1996-1998 (Box 33, Folder 2)
- Public Private Ventures (96621) - Mentoring Youth: The Community Change for Youth Development Project, Phase II - Background Materials (Box 33, Folder 3)
- Public Private Ventures (96621) - Mentoring Youth: The Community Change for Youth Development Project, Phase II - Grant Products, 1996-1998 (Box 33, Folder 4-5)
- Public Private Ventures (970932) - The State and Future of Mentoring, 1997-1998 (Box 34, Folder 1)
- Public Private Ventures (970932) - The State and Future of Mentoring - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 34, Folder 2)
- Public Private Ventures (970932) - The State and Future of Mentoring - Grant Products, 1998-1999 (Box 34, Folder 3-4)
- University of Rochester (94-42) - Youth Mentoring Program (Box 34, Folder 5)
- Vanderbilt University Hospital (96039, 96998, 94-43), 1993-1997 (Box 34, Folder 6)
- Washington Hospital Center (96999, 96040, 94-44) - The Hospital Youth Mentoring Program, 1994-1998 (Box 34, Folder 7)
- Yale University, Department of Psychology - Marsland, 1997 (Box 35, Folder 1)
- Child Development Audiovisual material, 1
  Sound recordings; Moving Images
  - Healthy Steps for Young Children Multimedia Package Video: 1) Teachable Moments: Infants (18:50); 2) Family Factors (27:50); 3) Tools for Gauging Development (28:35), 1999 June 3; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11752)
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please see a RAC archivist for further instruction.
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Additional VHS copy located Box: 1 [A0000000089572].
  - I Am Your Child: Ready to Learn, Hosted by Jamie Lee Curtis and LeVar Burton, VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11753)
  - I Am Your Child: Quality Child Care: Making the Right Choice for You and Your Child, Hosted by Maria Shriver, VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11754)
  - I Am Your Child: Discipline: Teaching Limits With Love, Hosted by Dr. T. Berry Brazelton, VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11755)
  - Begin with Love: The First Three Months: Connecting with Your Child, with Oprah Winfrey, VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11756)
  - Comprehensive Care for Children, Advocate Health Care, 13 minutes; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11757)
  - Comprehensive Care for Children, VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11758)
  - Healthy Steps Seminar, Advocate Health Care, 1999 October 26; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11759)
  - Healthy Steps for Young Children. Highlights from Teachable Moments: Infants, 5 minutes; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11760)
  - Escape Fire, VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11761)
  - Investigative Reports: Every Parents Nightmare, VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11762)
  - Big Issues in the Next Ten Years of Improvement - Donald M. Berkwick, MD, MPP. NICHQ First Annual Forum on Improving Children's Healthcare, 2002 March 12-13; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11763)
  - Kathryn Taffe Young/Children - Morning Edition, NPR-AM/Network, 6:00AM, 1998 April 3; 6 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 11764)
    Scope and Contents
    Kathryn Taffe Young discusses the Commonwealth Fund survey regarding parent satisfaction with their children's pediatric care.